BLOG: https://medium.com/@jennyjean8675309 | LINKEDIN: www.linkedin.com/in/jenny-j-ingram/

JENNIFER INGRAM

Full stack web developer with a background in education who discovered the joys of coding while teaching at a science museum. With experience in Ruby, JS, React, and Redux, I love building things that help others enrich their lives. Ever curious, I bring strong skills in communicating complex ideas, and in understanding and implementing a project's requirements based on clients' needs.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Rock, Paper, Scissors, Fight! - Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo - Based on the classic game

- A React App incorporating Redux for an organized frontend, using JS for game flow logic
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and local Storage to encrypt and store sensitive user data
- Managed multiple state changes using Redux store

Cabinets of Curiosity — <u>Github Frontend</u> | <u>Github Backend</u> | <u>Demo</u> — A place for people to share their perspective of the world through a digital collection

- Created a backend API with Ruby on Rails
- Rendered user-generated UI changes with React; styled frontend using Semantic UI
- Validated users and encrypted sensitive information using JSON Web Tokens

Musee - Github | Demo - A museum review website for museum visitors and professionals alike

- Pair-programmed project using Ruby on Rails; used RESTFUL conventions and MVC standards
- Incorporated user authentication and authorization with a sessions controller and cookies
- Developed analytics using user-generated data; wrote RSpec tests

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Ruby, Rails, OOP, SQL, Javascript, React, Redux, Postgres, Git, Semantic-UI, JSON

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Infinity Science Center (a NASA visitor center), Pearlington, MS – Educator Mar. 2017 - May 2018

- Engaged visitors through educational activities, presentations, and classroom instruction
- Interpreted Saturn V mechanics to create signage for the museum's most popular artifact
- Built floor piano to teach guests about electricity see it on <u>Instructables.com</u>

DGF Elementary School, Rota Naval Base, Rota Spain - Art Teacher

Sep. 2014 - Jun. 2015

- Provided a broad view of the art world by combining art history, art criticism and art appreciation ideas with hands-on creative processes
- Presented subject matter in accordance with school curriculum guidelines and collaborated with other classroom teachers to enhance school curriculum

Shmoop.com (remote) - Art History Curriculum Writer

Sep. 2014 - Dec. 2016, part-time

• Wrote Art History curriculum projects (for high school + students) that included coursework, test-prep, and college-prep materials that met a variety of academic standards

EDUCATION

Flatiron School, Washington D.C.

Oct. 2018 - Jan. 2019

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails, and Javascript immersive program

University of Idaho, Moscow, ID

Aug. 1997 - May 2002

B.S. Art Education (3.60 GPA)